DAVIDE GHIOTTO

March, 2021

(VI) Italy | dghiotto.careers@gmail.com | linkedin: davide-ghiotto | github: davide97g | portfolio: davideghiotto.it

CURRICULUM VITAE

CARRIER PROFILE

Full Stack Developer with 18 months of experience implementing custom Angular Web Applications and core Java microservices, for large scale use in the banking sector. Developed reusable components and effective models to keep the pace with continuous delivery of high quality products.

Core competences include: Angular Framework, Java 8, Node.js, web API, TypeScript, JavaScript, SQL, Oracle Database, MongoDB, Spring, Git, HTML, CSS, Sass.

EXPERIENCE

Reply S.p.A - Cluster & Core Financial Services

Nov 2019 to present

Full Stack Developer & Database Manager

Developed complete Angular Web Applications, integrated with *backend* Java *API*, in a microservice oriented architecture, in order to build a large scale platform capable of handling the complexity of financial services world.

Managed a massive database migration to a SQL Server environment.

Implemented high quality code to speed up further developments and lower maintenance work in a continuous delivery environment.

- Created a generalized conceptual model to efficiently handle user interactions and data flow leading to an uniformed solution capable of avoid potential error situations and repetitive work
- Implemented a decentralized error handling strategy to avoid single point of failure with an increased reliability of the system
- ullet Improved data retrieval time through careful analysis and optimization of database's requests along with asynchronous client-side code
- Accelerated the procedure of database migration thanks to the development of scripts for automated quality control

Zucchetti S.p.A Nodejs Developer

May 2019 to July 2019

Stage

Developed a Nodejs application that grouped together different machine learning methods under a common interface. Presented the visual results of the algorithms on a web page transpiling the server side code into ES6 modules with Webpack.

- Created a common graphical interface to interact uniformly with different machine learning methods
- Implemented state-of-the-art training algorithm for Support Vector Machines to achieve better performance thanks to a deep mathematical analysis

TECHNICAL SKILLS

- Web technologies: Angular, TypeScript, JavaScript, HTML, CSS, Sass
- Backend technologies: Nodejs, Java, Python, Spring
- Database: MongoDB, MySQL, POSTGRES, ORACLE
- Cloud Platform: Firebase, Google Cloud Platform, Heroku
- Statistics: R, Python, Pandas
- Versioning: Git, Github, Bitbucket

EDUCATION

Master's Degree Data Science

University of Study of Padua

2019 to present

Bachelor's Degree Computer Science

University of Study of Padua

110L/110

2016-2019

Highschool Graduation

29.1/30 weighted average

Liceo Scientifico Statale G.B. Quadri

2011-2016

87/100 **CERTIFICATES**

• **B2** First, 2015

OTHER SKILLS

Languages English: professional proficiency. Italian: native.